原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     折千纸鹤的小熊    米帅家的薇薇安
翻译     普利星布里狗     肉塔     四月
翻译     徐棒棒     木浅     姚老师越狱实验室
翻译     高庭玫瑰      PiPi
鸣谢       救火后期   爱的抱抱查
校对     木浅
校对     普利星布里狗
校对     何何SAMA丶就是丶海皇波塞冬  信不
校对     匡老湿
时间轴    爱的抱抱查     浪影书构狐狸河
时间轴    全身纹大葱
WEB版    时间轴   何何SAMA丶就是丶海皇波塞冬  信不
后期     填坑的渔夫不纹身
特效     何何SAMA丶就是丶海皇波塞冬  信不
精校     何何SAMA丶就是丶海皇波塞冬  信不
总监     何何SAMA丶就是丶海皇波塞冬  信不
最新海外影视剧下载
人人词典
使用人人词典查词学习，美剧原声朗读与例句场景
Prison Break
微信扫描
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
我之前打电话询问关于一名在中东失踪的美国公民
I called earlier about a missing U.S. citizen in the Middle East.
你好吗  莎拉
How are you, Sara?
我想要国务院的帮忙  不是你
I wanted the State Department, not you.
波塞冬有没有可能让我们直接杀了她
Any chance Poseidon will just let us kill her?
我搞清楚了一些有关于
I've learned some things
我们两个都在找的那个人的事
about who it is we're apparently both looking for.
你认为迈克尔在也门
You think Michael's in Yemen?
我们会把你救出来的
We're gonna get you out of here.
我不知道你们是谁
I don't know who you are.
这家店是你弟弟越狱计划的一部分
Your brother was using this shop for his escape.
我们来拿护照
We're here for passports.
我们应该还有一天时间离开这鬼地方
Figure we got a day to get out of this hole.
我们还是会逃出去的  我们所有人
We're still getting out. All of us.
你为我们安排好出去的路了吗
是的  就在明晚
波塞冬把我们安排到这里去救拉马尔
Poseidon put us in here to get Ramal out,
但他又抛弃了我们
but then he abandoned us.
拉马尔是波塞冬的人  不是我们的
Ramal's Poseidon's guy, not ours.
他跟我说过越狱的事情
Our friend told me about the escape.
他会抛弃你的
He will betray you.
等那些灯都灭了
When those lights go black,
我们会像幽灵一样从这里消失不见
we're gonna disappear from this place like ghosts.
我打不开
I can't get it open.
帮帮我
Help me out.
你们先把我弟弟拉上去
You pull my brother up first.
穆萨  穆萨
Muza! Muza!
别开枪
Don't shoot.
也门
萨那
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
身体还好
Body is fine.
但我的头还在想
My head is trying to figure out
怎么弄到昨晚没拿到的护照
how to get those passports we couldn't get last night.
你的和那些孩子的
For you, those kids.
你现在不需要考虑这件事
Well, that's something you shouldn't be worrying about right now.
好好休息  我们还需要你
You should rest up. We're gonna need you.
到我死时就能好好休息了
I can rest when I'm dead.
我担心的就是这个
Well, that's what I'm worried about.
没想到你还会担心
Didn't know you worried.
该担心的我都会担心
About the right things.
你弟弟
Your brother.
他逃出来了吗
He make it out?
-抱歉  -没事
- I'm sorry. - Yeah.
希巴  我和林肯聊一会儿  好吗
Sheba, do you mind if I borrow Linc for a second?
-好的  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
好好休息
Please get some rest.
我们得谈谈该怎么离开这个国家了
Listen. We got to start talking about leaving the country.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我和清真寺的朋友谈过了
I spoke to my friends at the mosque.
ISIL攻下这附近的速度可以以小时计
ISIL is taking neighborhoods by the hour.
如果他们切断去往机场的路
If they cut off the route to the airport...
我不会丢下迈克尔
I'm not leaving Michael.
如果他们切断去机场的路
If they cut off the airport,
就没人能离开了
no one is getting out.
你  我  希巴都不能
Not you, me, Sheba.
尽管我很不想这么说
As much as it kills me to say...
我们不能在一个人身上
we can't risk all of it for...
孤注一掷
just one man.
你说的没错
You're right.
你可以离开
You can leave.
但我不能
But I can't.
把那一家人尽快送到机场
Get that family to the airport as fast as you can.
我自己会另想办法
I'll work something out.
布鲁斯先生
Mr. Burrows?
我来感谢你救了我的女儿
I wanted to thank you for saving my daughter.
而且我想回报你
And offer you something in appreciation.
我也许有办法
I might have a solution
把你的弟弟从监狱里救出来
for how to get your brother out of that prison,
赶在这座城市沦为地狱之前
before the city goes to hell.
也门
奥杰吉亚监狱
你听见了吗
You hear that?
迄今为止最近的一颗炮弹
That was the closest one yet!
90多米远
100 yards!
正当大家觉得没什么能比被关禁闭更糟时
Just when you think it couldn't get worse locked up in a Porta Potti,
这里就开始下900多公斤的炸弹雨了
they start dropping 2,000-pound bombs on the Porta Potti.
维普  冷静  拜托
Whip. Keep it together, please.
我们的越狱大师现在也紧张了
The escape artist is nervous.
你也该觉得紧张
You should be, too.
那些砸下来的炮弹
Those artillery strikes,
可不长眼
they don't discriminate.
区别在于我有信仰
The difference is I have faith.
真主会拯救我
Allah will deliver me.
你又有什么
What do you have?
雅  雅  你在吗
Ja! Ja, are you there?
我在
I'm here.
维普是对的
Whip's right.
炮击越来越近了
The strikes are getting closer.
我挺可怜你
I pity you.
不管怎样我都赢了
I triumph either way.
要么我会上天堂
Either I will be in paradise
要么真主会拯救我
or Allah will save me.
而你  你就要死了
You, you're just going to die.
ISIL的军队已经攻破了关卡
ISIL has broken through the checkpoints.
他们就要攻进城了
They're coming into the city.
穿着这身制服  我们就是活靶子
These uniforms are like targets on our backs.
ISIL的人还没打到这呢
ISIL isn't here yet.
政府说会击退他们的
The government says it will push them back.
你疯了吗  面对现实吧
You out of your head? This is happening.
萨那就要沦陷了
Sana'a is falling.
他们要撤退了
They're going to retreat.
我以前在军队里见过那种表情
I've seen that look before in the army.
那是会想方设法寻求自保的人
Men who will do anything to save themselves.
那我们要怎么自保
And how do we save ourselves?
ISIL拿下这座监狱
ISIL takes this prison,
我们会是第一批死在屠刀下的人
we'll be the first they slaughter.
等他们拿下这座监狱
When they take this prison,
会去解救他们的领导人拉马尔
it will be to liberate their leader, Ramal,
但如果他们到这时
but if when they get here,
我们拿刀顶着他的喉咙
we have him with a knife to his throat,
那就是我们说了算
then we call the shots.
我们可能会活下来
And we might just live.
维普  我要来个"万福玛利亚"[又指 孤注一掷之意]
Whip, I got a Hail Mary.
-是祈祷还是计划  -计划
- That a prayer or a plan? - Plan.
上次我被关在这时  留下了点东西
I left something the last time I was in here.
让我猜猜  你有个应急计划
Let me guess, you got a contingency.
他们关了我四年禁闭
They lock me away in a box for four years.
我才不会就干坐在那里
I'm not just gonna sit there.
不一定能成功  但没准能让我们逃出去
It's a long shot, but it might get us out.
异教徒还打着越狱的算盘
The infidel still tries to escape.
绝望的叛徒
The desperate rat.
等我们从这逃出去  绝望的叛徒会干死你
The desperate rat's gonna light you up once we get out of here,
-你这个突眼泡的丑八怪  -维普
- you bugged-eyed freak. - Whip.
维普  有个"S"
Whip! An "S."
角落处齐胸高的墙上有没有一个刻着的"S"
Is there an "S" carved in your wall chest high in the corner?
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on.
这个不是
That's not it.
我什么都没看见
I'm not seeing anything.
我没看见
I'm not seeing it.
雅  那一定是你了
Ja, it's got to be you.
快点  告诉我在你的墙上刻着"S"
Come on. Tell me you got an "S" carved in your wall.
-这是我们最后的机会了  -没有
- It's our last chance. - No.
不在这  没有
It's not here, no.
那是因为在我的禁闭室里有
That's because I have it in my cell.
我的"哈里发"王国军队越来越近了
My armies of the caliphate are coming closer.
等他们一到这个地方
The moment they reach this place,
你们都会像狗一样被处死
all of you will be put down like the dogs that you are.
纽约州
美 国 国 务 院
好的  莎拉
All right, Sara.
我们的朋友波塞冬露面了
Our friend, Poseidon, has surfaced.
老天爷啊
Good God.
又一波ISIL恐怖组织的攻击
Another ISIL attack.
他们要把这座城市变为废墟了
They're ripping the city apart.
一群畜生
They're animals.
我当了一辈子官
I've been a bureaucrat my whole life.
也恨透了官场
Hated it.
贪污腐败  虚情假意  狼狈为奸
Corruption, backslapping.
不过今天  当官可能还有点好处
But today, maybe some good will come of it.
我曾和一个叫易卜拉欣的男孩一起读初中
I went to grammar school with this boy named Ibrahim.
过去这么多年  他现在是一名联邦法官
All the years later, he's a federal judge.
你是说这名法官能帮我们
You, saying this judge can help us?
我几个小时前给他打过电话
I called him a few hours ago
把你弟弟的案子告诉了他
and told him about your brother's case.
也门
萨那
司法部
想重新装修呢  是吧
Redecorating, I see.
只是为即将到来的变天做准备
Just readying for the coming change of seasons.
奢侈品是瓦哈比教派看不惯的东西
Luxury is something the Wahhabists frown upon,
[一个极度保守的极端主义伊斯兰教派  催生恐怖主义的根源之一]
所以奢侈品得藏起来
so luxury will stay behind closed doors.
你应该逃离这个国家
You should flee the country.
我在哪都能活下去  你知道的
I'm a survivor, you know that.
我想布鲁斯先生或许能帮得上他弟弟的事
I thought Mr. Burrows could perhaps help with his brother's cause.
是的
Yes.
最高司法委员会颁发的完全赦免令
A full pardon from the Supreme Judicial Council.
但你得兑现你的承诺  雅米尔
But you will have to uphold your end of the bargain, Jamil.
德国工艺  七万七千英里里程
German engineering. 77,000 miles.
5升  7速变速箱  V10发动机
Five liter, seven speed, V10.
它将有很高的收藏价值
It will be a welcome bit of luxury.
自然是要秘密收藏起来
Behind closed doors, of course.
祝你们两个好运
Best of luck to both of you.
真的很感谢你  谢谢
I really appreciate this. Thank you.
已经是这样了
It's already done.
不管怎样它都会被丢在这里
It would've been left behind anyhow.
希望我们两家人今晚都能平安离开萨那
May both of our families get safely out of Sana'a tonight.
我们不能坐以待毙
We can't just sit here and die.
你也有一扇这样的窗户  对吗
You-you got a window like this one, right?
也许我们能撬开它
Maybe we can pry it.
它太小太坚固了
It's too small, reinforced.
被铸入钢筋基础设施里了
Built into the rebar infrastructure.
你外头有人  对吗
You got people on the outside, right?
他们会努力把我们救出去的
And they're gonna try and get us out.
他们本应昨晚在商店和我们汇合
They were supposed to meet us at the shop last night
但我们没有出现
and we didn't show.
我们不能就这样放弃
We can't just quit
-任凭波塞冬打败我们  -拉马尔
- and let Poseidon beat us. - Ramal?
如果我们合作  就会有出去的办法
There's a way out if we work together,
但越狱必须从你的牢房里开始
but escape has to start from your cell.
我已经没兴趣了
I'm no longer interested.
你现在唯一能做的就是求我
The only thing left for you to do is to beg.
求我当我的大军来临之时  我也许会放你一条生路
Beg that I might let you live once my armies came,
但也只能是以奴隶的身份
if only as a slave.
我在过去七年里一直是奴隶
I've been a slave for the last seven years.
我不会再继续下去了
I won't do it anymore!
你死了我会想念你
I will miss you when you're dead,
不过也就想那么一小会儿
but only for a minute.
然后你就会被时间和这个世界遗忘
Then you will be forgotten by both time and the world.
她也是我的孩子  辛迪
Well, she's my kid, too, Cindy.
我分到了周末和...
I have the weekends and...
不  我要周末
Well, no, I have the weekends
我不想要周三下午
and I don't want a Wednesday afternoon.
我怎么会想要那天呢
Why would I want that?
是的  没人想要
Yeah, nobody does.
没事的  辛迪
No, that's okay, Cindy.
没事  还有哪几天
Yeah, that's fine. What other days?
你还想要哪几天
What other days do you want?
你知道吗  我现在不想讨论这个
Actually you know what? I don't want to discuss this now.
不  我们以后再谈
No, we'll talk about it later.
再见
Bye.
自我被释放以来  这世上
Of all the things that mystify me in this world
令我最困惑的事是
since I've been released,
现今居然时兴甘蓝汁了
is that kale is the rage.
甘蓝汁
Kale.
西尔多·拜格威尔
Theodore Bagwell.
同样令我困惑的是
Thing that mystifies me equally
七年前
is seven years ago,
你赦免了迈克尔  林肯和其他所有人
you exonerated Michael, Lincoln, all of them,
却没有我
except me.
-是吗  -爽
- Really? - Yes!
这是你来这的原因吗
That's why you're here?
就因为我没赦免你吗
Because I didn't exonerate you?
赦免一个谋杀犯
A murderer,
罪行累累的淫魔
a sexual predator a dozen times over.
关键词是"曾经是"
"Was" is the key word.
哥现在可是个弃暗投明之人了
I'm a man moving toward the light now,
光明在召唤着我
and the light's beckoning me.
我只是不知道谁在背后操纵
I just don't know who's pulling the strings.
但莎拉说是你
But Sara says it's you.
莎拉让你来找我的吗
Sara put you onto me?
好吧  我不知道你和她谁更蠢
Okay. I don't know who the bigger idiot is, you or her.
我那是在帮她
I was helping her.
你黑进了她的手机
You were hacking her phone
还派人追杀她
and sending those people after her--
不许... 撒谎
Don't... lie.
现在
Now...
不如你给哥倒杯那种恶心的甘蓝汁喝吧
how about you pour me one of them nasty little kale jobbies,
告诉我这一切跟我和斯科菲尔德有什么关系
and tell me what's all this got to do with Scofield and myself,
你的同伙是谁  你又是谁
who your friends are, who you are--
我想彻底看清那个想操纵我的人的真面目
I want to see the true face of who's pulling my strings once and for all.
在大厅里有两个人找你
You have two visitors in the lobby.
告诉他们我很快下去
Tell them I'll be right down.
这个我来搞定  格蕾丝
I got this, Grace.
他们攻进城里了
They're in the city.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你觉得呢
What do you think I'm doing?
别跑  你个混蛋
Don't run, you dog!
别跑
Don't run!
要开始了  准备好
It is happening. Be ready.
这个赦免令最好能救他出来
This pardon better get him out of here.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time--
我们得找到监狱长
we have to get to the warden.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
他们要放弃这座监狱了
They're abandoning the prison.
那就是易卜拉欣同意特赦的原因
That's why Ibrahim gave us that pardon.
他知道特赦已没什么意义了
He knew it was worthless.
你和钞票哥带着其他人尽快前往机场
You and C-Note get the others to the airport as fast as you can--
或许还有一次离境的航班
there's maybe one flight out.
留两个座位  知道了吗
Save two seats. All right?
你要去干什么
What are you going to do?
我要去救我弟
I'm gonna get my brother.
穆斯塔法
Mustapha!
退后  退后
Back up! Back up.
靠近者死  明白了吗
Anyone comes at me, dies. Understand?
你觉得你能射杀我们所有人吗
You think you can shoot all of us?
还有人想碰运气吗
Anyone else want to play the lottery?
你们这群废物
You're filth.
ISIL的人会解决你们的
I'll let ISIL sort you out.
穆斯塔法
Mustapha!
穆斯塔法  穆斯塔法  等一下
Mustapha! Mustapha, wait!
别把我锁在这里
Don't lock me in here!
你这个懦夫
You coward.
穆斯塔法  拜托了
Mustapha, please.
懦夫
Coward!
我要进去
I need to get in!
我要出去
I need to get out!
给我钥匙
Well, give me the key.
我没有钥匙
I don't have the key.
带钥匙的人刚从你身边过去
You passed the guy who does.
退后  我不想杀你们
Stay back! I don't want to shoot you!
狱警们都跑了
The guards are gone!
他们放弃了坚守自己的岗位
They're abandoning their posts!
我们要重获自由了
We're gonna be free!
不  我们不会自由
No. We're not free.
情况只会变得更糟
Things just got a lot worse.
把门撞开
Push the gate open!
停下
Stop!
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
我们得冲出这道门
We have to get through the gate!
如果如他们所说
If ISIL controls the city,
ISIL掌控了这座城市  那出去也是监狱
like they say, it will be a prison out there as well.
我们会像过去在这一样被审判  而且只会更糟
We will be persecuted, as we have been in here, only worse!
至少还有一线生机
At least there's a chance!
你想要机会吗
You want a chance?
我们的机会在那  就在禁闭室里
Our chance lies in there, in solitary.
我们谈判的筹码
Our bargaining chip.
我们抓住阿布·拉马尔
We get Abu Ramal!
我们可以以此换取一条出城的路
We negotiate passage out of the country.
不  你疯了吧
No, it's madness.
来吧  我们齐心协力就能撞开这扇门
Come on. If we work together, we can push open the gate.
是你吗  小公举
Is that you, Princess?
就是你  我们记得他  对吗
It is you. We remember this one! Right?
-我们记得他  -求你...
- We remember him! - Please...
那个不愿意帮我弟的
Friend to Kaniel Outis,
卡尼尔·乌提斯的朋友
the man who would not lend my brother a hand!
在我看来  就是那个人害死了我弟  对吧
The man who killed my brother, as far as I'm concerned, right?
-我们要进去抓住阿布·拉马尔  -不
- We are going to go in there and get Abu Ramal! - No! Please!
-不  求你了  -等我们进去时
- No! Please! - And when we are there,
我要亲手割开卡尼尔·乌提斯的咽喉
I am personally going to slice Kaniel Outis' throat.
你将是那个帮我达到目的的人
And you are going to be the one who's going to help me do it.
-不  -你抓住他
- No! - You take him!
抓住他
Take him!
所有人听着
All of you!
你们要待在这里吗
Will you stay here?
你们要让ISIL杀了你们吗
And let ISIL slaughter you?
还是你们愿意与我联手
Or will you stand with me?
反抗到底
And fight!
听起来情况不妙
Doesn't sound very promising!
拉马尔  你要不要重新考虑一下帮我们
Ramal, you want to rethink helping us?
越狱必须从你的牢房里开始
Escape has to start from your cell!
你们这些异教徒都该下地狱
All you infidels can go to Hell!
我们已经身处地狱了  拉马尔
We are in Hell, Ramal.
问题是你想不想出去
Question is do you want out?
撞开这扇门
Smash through the door!
告诉我怎么做
Tell me what to do.
喂  警察
我不是警察
那你裤子上的条纹是怎么回事
证件
快拿出来  不然我们开枪了  听懂了吗
他有枪
我谁的手机都没黑
I'm not hacking anybody's phones.
这件事上你大错特错了  根本不了解情况
You're so off base on this, you have no idea.
是吗
Am I?
是... 是的
Y-Yes.
对了  这太难喝了
That is terrible, by the way.
你这是做什么  想表达忏悔吗
What is that, an act of contrition?
想自我惩罚吗
Like a hair shirt?
用甘蓝汁折磨自己来弥补罪过吗
Torture yourself with Kale to make up for your sins?
我不再有任何罪过了  哥们
I don't have any sins anymore, man.
-有罪的是你  -那欺骗之罪呢
- That's you. - How about the sin of deceit?
白天是个名叫凯勒曼  喝甘蓝汁的人
A kale-drinking man named Kellerman by the light of day,
晚上却是中情局杀人不眨眼的禽兽波塞冬
a murderous CIA rogue named Poseidon at night.
波塞冬
Poseidon?
眼睛放光喽  被她说中了
His eyes light up. She was right.
你觉得我是波塞冬吗
Oh, you think I'm Poseidon?
好吧
Okay.
你是不是搅和进了波塞冬的事了
Are you mixed up with Poseidon?
这事还得要老办法解决吗
Oh, hell, we got to go old school with this?
你非要这样吗
Is that what you want?
尝尝哥的"断指神功"
T-Bag snapping fingers.
你刚给了我一点能配合你的线索
That's very-- you just gave me something to work with.
波塞冬吗  那就波塞冬
Poseidon? Poseidon.
我把我知道的波塞冬的事都告诉你
I'll tell you about Poseidon.
他是你在这个体制中能听说的传奇之一
I mean, he's one of those myths you hear about in the system.
这个特工触不可及
He's an operative so untouchable,
深不可测  就算你用核潜艇都找不到他
so deep, you couldn't find him with a nuclear sub.
所以才有了这个外号
Hence the nickname.
这跟我怎么扯上关系的
And how does this involve me?
他想要迈克尔做什么
What's he want with Michael?
拉马尔  仔细听着
Ramal, listen closely.
刻着"S"的那块砖  是松的
The brick with the "S," It's loose.
你得把它挪开
You got to remove it.
里面有一把勺子  一根绳子
It's a spoon, string.
怎么弄到的
How?
绳子是四年来从我囚服上一丝一线拆下来积攒的
A string a day from my uniforms for four years.
勺子是好不容易趁狱警没注意拿到手的
A spoon a guard overlooked one time in a thousand.
你头顶上方有根水管
There's a water pipe above you.
钩住它  拽下来
Hook it, pull it down.
抓紧
Do it!
我确认一下  你这是要帮他逃出去吗
Let me get this straight. This is getting him out?
是让我们一起逃出去
It's getting us all out.
这活儿需要我和对面牢房的他合作完成
This is a two-cell job, mine and his.
所以当初我在他那个牢房时没能成功
That's why I couldn't pull it off when I was in that cell,
因为我对面这个牢房里的人不愿意合作
because the guy across from me, the guy in this cell, wouldn't cooperate.
我们必须合作
We have to work together.
来吧
Come on!
-不  -克劳斯
- No. - Cross!
我不会跟你合作
I'm not working with you.
不
No.
过来  来吧  宝贝
Come here! Come on, sweetheart.
让他们看看你的漂亮脸蛋  来吧  上来
Show them your pretty face! Come on, get up here!
听着  赶紧给我停下
Look! Stop what you're doing
告诉卡尼尔·乌提斯我会杀了这"娘们"
and tell Kaniel Outis I will kill the girl!
抓住他
Take him!
来呀  我跟你还没完呢
Come on! I'm not through with you yet!
他们把希德打得不成样子了
They're beating the crap out of Sid.
我们不投降的话  他们会杀了他的
They'll kill him unless we surrender.
如果我们投降了  他们也会杀了我们
If we surrender, they'll kill us.
他们只想要拉马尔
They only want Ramal.
我们只有自己先逃出去才是救希德的最好办法
Our best chance of saving Sid is getting out of here.
让他们忘了他  追着我们跑
Make them forget about him, start chasing us.
很好
Okay, good.
捡起来  系上绳子  把它穿过去
Now pick it up. String the cord and pull it through.
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
好
Yeah!
我会杀了这"娘们"  我发誓
I will kill the girl, I swear it!
不
No!
我不会再重复
I won't say it again,
这个监狱里不许出人命
there will not be any killing in this prison!
在我眼皮底下就不行
Not on my watch!
这简直是疯了
This is completely insane.
外面简直乱成一锅粥了
It's a freakin' Mexican soap opera out here!
拉马尔  别停下  别动歪脑筋
Ramal, don't stop. Don't start thinking.
别把你的希望寄托在区区一个狱警身上
Don't pin your hopes on one guard.
走开
Walk away!
藏到牢房里去
Hide in the cell block!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
这监狱完蛋了  哥们
The prison is done, brother.
看在上帝的份上
For the love of God!
看在真主的份上  一个有志于寻求正义之士
For the love of God, a man seeks justice.
他的一举一动  无时无刻不在加以践行
In everything he does, at all times!
现在  所有人  都回牢区去
Now, everybody, back in the block!
不再有什么犯人和狱警了
There are no prisoners and guards anymore!
你意识到了吧
You realize that, right?
要是ISIL的人进来了
If ISIL gets in here,
我们都是他们的敌人
we are all the enemy,
都是罪人
sinners,
离经叛道者
deviants...
是把他们的领袖关起来的人
and those that locked up their leader.
而你是他们能抓到的唯一一个狱警
You will be the only guard that they catch.
有道德的狱警
The noble one.
他们会为此砍了你的头  但是...
They will behead you for it. But...
如果我们合作
if we work together,
抓住拉马尔
we get Ramal,
我们就有了谈判的筹码
we have a bargaining chip.
我会确保
I will see to it
你会和我们一起逃出去
that you will get out with the rest of us.
只要你给我禁闭室的钥匙
Just give me the keys to solitary.
-我没有钥匙  -我知道你有
- I don't have the keys. - I know you do.
加入我们  你就能活下去
Join us and you will live.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
我没有钥匙
I don't have them.
杀了他
Kill him!
但你有更好的东西  对吧
But you have something much better, huh?
让开  让开
Move. Move!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊  他们杀了那个狱警
Oh, my God. They killed the guard!
还拿了他的枪  冲着我们来了
They got his gun! They're coming for us!
得把握这个时机啊  拉马尔
Got to make this count, Ramal.
把"钓鱼竿"从那个槽里穿出来
String that fishing pole through that slot.
就这样
That's right.
这样你就可以把我门轴上的小齿轮去掉
Now, you can remove the pinions on my door-- the hinges.
有两个
There are two of them.
行不通
No way.
你想干什么
What are you doing?
我要去掉我自己的
I'm doing mine.
我们没时间这么瞎折腾了  拉马尔
We don't have time for this, Ramal!
我说了这活儿要两个牢房合作  这才是关键
I'm telling you, it's a two-cell job, that's the point.
那一侧是新建的
That side of the wing is new construction.
小齿轮被做在门轴铰链里  你没法拔出来
The pinions are covered in the hinges-- you can't pull them.
这边是原来建的  门轴是开的  很松
This side is original. They're open, loose.
你想让我放你出来吗
You want me to free you?
对  然后我用那边的钥匙把你的门打开
Yes, and I, in turn, free you with those keys, down there.
你就比外面的疯子可信吗
Why would I trust you more than the madman out there?
因为你刚也听出了他是多么言而无信
'Cause you just heard what his word is worth.
踢开它
Kick it.
就这样了  就看你相信谁的话了
This is it. It's all about whose word you trust.
我保证  只要你放了我
I promise you-- you release me,
我就放了你
I release you.
再来一点  再来一点
Little more, little more.
谢天谢地  快
Thank God. Come on.
好了  弄下面那个
Okay, the bottom.
对  就这样
Yes!
快  快
Come on, come on.
-快  -快
- Come on. - Come on.
就这样
Yes!
马上就开了
Almost there!
-太好了  -给点力啊
- Yes. - Come on.
得快点了  加把劲
Got to hurry up, come on.
太好了  快
Yes. Yes, come on!
你要去哪
Where are you going?
快打开我的门
Open my door.
我要出去
I'm getting the hell out of here.
把我的门打开
Open my door.
别管他了  你疯了吗
Leave him, man, you crazy?
把我的门打开
Open my door.
等我们逃出了监狱
Once we're outside these walls,
我们需要安全逃出这个国家
we need safe passage out of the country.
都到现在了  你还讨价还价
Even now, you negotiate.
要么我们合作  要么我们一起死
We work together or we both die.
我向你保证
You have my word.
开门
Open the door.
我们得走了
We got to go now.
不  不
No, no!
"嘀嗒糖侠"
Mr. Tic Tac.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
你要去打ISIL的人吗
You gonna fight ISIL men?
快走  孩子  躲起来
Get out of here, kid, hide!
-这里太危险  -你要去打ISIL的人吗
- This is no place for you. - You gonna fight ISIL men?
对
Yes.
认真听我说  好吗
Listen very closely, all right?
美国人  美国人  美国人
American! American! American!
那里有个美国人
什么
就在那个转角  他想来打你们
我们走
我们去检查这个街区
-你要去找"泡泡糖侠"吗  -对
- You go to Bubble Gum Man now? - Yeah.
谢谢你帮忙  给  拿着
Thanks for your help. Here, take that.
去个安全的地方  好吗
Get somewhere safe, okay?
"嘀嗒糖侠"去救"泡泡糖侠"啦
Mr. Tic Tac goes to Bubble Gum Man!
拉马尔  我不想杀你
Ramal... don't want to kill you.
只想杀你的同伴  明白吗
Just your friends. You understand?
我们来这里做什么  这帮不了我们
What are we doing in here? This is not helping us.
你要打个电话
You're gonna make a phone call
这样你才能兑现你的承诺
so you can hold up your end of the deal.
在纳什万广场有一家汽修店
There's an auto body shop off Nashwan Plaza.
我要几辆车  加满油
I want vehicles there, full tanks of gas
这样我们所有人就能到达边境
so we can get to the border, all of us.
我不会跟你们去边境
I'm not going with you to the border.
你没得选
You don't have a choice.
我们会开车到边境  然后说再见
We're gonna ride to the border, then say sayonara.
你是我们的护身符
You're our insurance.
拉马尔  我不想杀你  明白吗
Ramal, I don't want to kill you. You understand?
还是说你想当他们的护身符
Or would you rather be their insurance?
拿着
Take it.
我想知道他说的什么  他可能要坑我们
I want to know what he's saying. He could be screwing us.
他就是想坑我们  好吧
He's screwing with us, all right.
我们只需要先下手为强
We just need to screw with him first.
雅在哪
Where's Ja?
不知道
I don't know.
-氧可酮  - 我们得撤了
- Oxycodone... ? - Hey, we got to peel.
[一种被广泛使用的止痛处方药  和吗啡一样有成瘾性]
扑热息痛[镇痛药]
Percocet...
快点  你个该死的日本瘾君子
Come on, you Japanese junkie son of a bitch.
我是韩国人  你个加拿大猴子
I'm Korean, you Canadian monkey.
加拿大  真有意思  雅
Canadian? Oh, that's really funny, Ja.
就算我们不被宰掉  我也会因为你笑死
I'd be splitting my sides if we weren't about to be slaughtered.
记住伍迪·艾伦说过的话
Remember what Woody Allen said.
[美国著名导演  编剧  演员]
他说过什么
What did he say?
"我不在乎死亡
"I don't mind dying.
只是当它到来之时  我不想在场"
I just don't want to be around when it happens."
[祈求快而无痛的死亡  抑或还没直面死亡的心理准备]
振作点
Hey, come on.
我们需要你  好吗
We need you, okay?
在耽搁些什么
What's the holdup?
检查下那边
斯科菲尔德必死无疑
Scofield's a dead man.
他跟波塞冬纠缠在一起
He's tangling with Poseidon.
我知道你打算做什么
I see what you're doing here.
说波塞冬就好像在提别人
Talking Poseidon in third person,
就好像你不是他
like you're not him.
国务院这些年来一直在找波塞冬
State Department has been looking for Poseidon for years,
你个笨蛋  他是个叛变的中情局特工
you idiot. He's a rogue CIA operative.
没人知道他是谁
Nobody knows who he is.
你就扯吧
Here we go?
我知道对你一个普通罪犯而言
I know it's a little above your pay grade
这有点超出你的理解范围
being a common criminal.
我是说  我们聊的是一个人  对吧
I mean, we're talking about a single man. Right?
一个很不喜欢白宫外交政策的主战派
A hawk who apparently doesn't like how the White House goes about foreign policy,
所以他决定亲自出马
and decided to take matters into his own hands.
不用军队  不用侵略
Not with armies, not with invasions,
而是通过杀死某个人
but by getting a single person killed,
通过让某个人当上政府要职
by getting a single person elected to office,
通过把某个人从监狱里放走
by getting a single person released from prison.
就像也门那个关押着迈克尔的监狱
Prison, like the one in Yemen, where Michael's at.
想知道我的想法吗
You want my guess?
阿布·拉马尔才是波塞冬想放走的人
It's Abu Ramal that Poseidon wants free.
那人我在监狱电视里见过
Guy I seen on the prison telly.
等等  我还以为中情局应该铲除恐怖分子
Wait, I thought the CIA was supposed to kill terrorists,
-而非放走他们  -波塞冬不再是中情局的了
- not release them. - Poseidon is no longer CIA.
他不为任何人工作
He doesn't report to anybody.
他只追求自己的理想
He just pursues his own ideology.
好吧  举个例子  听着
Okay, for instance, listen.
比如说你认为俄罗斯和伊朗
Let's say you think Russia and Iran
对中东的影响太大了
are having too much influence in the Middle East,
而你觉得华府不会把事情办好
and you don't think Washington is getting the job done.
那你就会放走拉马尔
You free Ramal.
没错  他的确是个伊斯兰激进份子
Sure, he's an Islamic radical nut job,
但他会为你去对抗伊朗和俄罗斯
but he will fight Iran and Russia for you.
敌人的敌人即为朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
而波塞冬最狡猾之处在于
And what's so shrewd about Poseidon
他做事不用任何网络
is he does it all without a network,
这也是他为什么这么难找的原因
which is why he's so hard to find.
区区一个人能操控到这个地步吗
One man can pull strings like that?
一个人操控一堆人
One man manipulating a handful of others.
阿布·拉马尔是个大魔头
Abu Ramal is a monster.
他就该下地狱
And there's a spot in Hell reserved for him,
不过最该堕入十八层地狱深处的要数波塞冬了
but the hottest spot is reserved for Poseidon,
因为他想放任拉马尔再一次搅乱这个世界
because he is letting Ramal loose on the world again.
那些人  他们的手上沾满了
Those men, they have the blood of thousands,
千千万万人的血
thousands on their hands.
跟他们比起来  你和我算得上两个天使
Compared to them, you and me are a couple of angels.
"天使"
"Angels"?
你弄清楚波塞冬是谁
You find out who Poseidon is,
斯科菲尔德又是怎么卷进去的
and how Scofield is wrapped up in it,
也许你的命运
maybe your fate...
就是要当个爱国者
is to be a patriot.
怎么...
What...?
跑  快跑
Go. Go!
万事万物皆有时[上天自有安排]
There's a time for everything.
911吗  我需要帮助  要快
911? I need help... now.
他们要从上面翻过去
They're going over the top.
我们走
Let's go.
快走  快走  快
Go, go, go, go, go!
这边
This way!
锁住了
It's locked!
是条死路
It's a dead end.
不  不  不  糟了  糟了
No, no, no, no. No. No, no, no, no.
拉马尔
Ramal?
藏起来
Hide!
我不想杀你  只想杀你的同伴
I don't want to kill you! Just your friends.
明白吗
You understand?
希德  你还活着啊
Sid, you're alive?
-能活多久还不一定呢  -拉马尔
- We'll see about that. - Ramal?!
我们把那混蛋交出去吧
Let's hand the son of a bitch over.
没用的
Won't work.
他们还是会杀了我们
They'll gun us down anyway.
那也不能在这等死啊
Can't just wait here and die.
你的戏演到头了
Your game is up.
赶紧出来
Come out!
任何挡在我和阿布·拉马尔之间的人都得死
Anyone who gets between me and Abu Ramal dies.
听懂了吗
You understand?!
拉马尔人呢
Where is Ramal?
快说
Tell me now!
有个男孩
There's a boy.
麦克·斯科菲尔德  在纽约州伊萨卡
Ithaca, New York. Mike Scofield.
要是我不能活着出去
If I don't make it out of here alive,
告诉他  他父亲很爱他
tell him his father loves him very much.
"他父亲"
"His father"?
如果我不阻止他开枪
If I don't smother that gun,
我们都得死
they'll kill us all.
后退
Move back!
后退  跑
Move back! Go!
让我过去
Let me through!
迈克尔  迈克尔
Michael! Michael!
Michael? Michael!
波塞冬派你来的吧
Poseidon sent you?
你朋友呢
Where's your friend?
他早跑了
He's long gone.
后门
Back door.
从里面锁住了
Locked from the inside.
他还在这里
He's in here.
找到他
Find him.
我也曾和你一样  为谎言而杀戮
I was you once, killing for a lie.
那你现在算什么
Now you're what?
为真相献身吗
Dying for the truth?
人总有揭开真相的天性
It's human nature to find stuff out,
你也会揭开真相
so you will.
或者她也会
Or she will.
到那时  为谎言卖命的就得杀死揭开真相的
And then the lie has to kill the truth.
你们两个中  谁会被谁杀死...
Which one of you is gonna die ne--?
该撤了
Time to get scarce.
他跟你说什么了
What did he say to you?
没什么
Nothing.
汽修店就在前面几条街
Auto shop's a few blocks up.
你的人最好在赶来的路上
And your men better be coming.
他们会赶到那的
They will be there.
雅去哪了
Where is Ja?
雅
Ja,
-你干什么呢  -我快饿死了
- what are you doing? - I'm starving, man.
知道我多久没见过水果了吗
You know how long it's been since I seen fruit?
你停下来就为了吃东西吗
You're stopping to eat?
你嗑药嗑疯了吗
Are you high?!
别质问我  你又不是我妈
Don't come at me, man. You're not my mama.
告诉你吧  你完了
You know what? You're done.
-你滚吧  -什么
- You're gone. - What?
-等等  -我让你滚  你就是个负担
- Wait. - I said, walk! You're a liability!
等等
Wait. Wait.
你说过要救我出来
You said you'd get me out,
送我到家的  我们说好的啊
all the way home. That was the deal.
拉马尔  这个人再跟着我们
Ramal, this man follows us,
就让你的人杀了他
tell your men to shoot him.
乐意之至
Gladly.
我们逃出生天之法
就藏在工作台下面
你去哪了  迈克尔
Where'd you go, Michael?
你跑哪去了
Where'd you go?
我们逃出生天之法
就藏在工作台下面
举起手来
弟兄们  你们来了啊
There you are, my men.
抓住这些狗东西  他们该死
Seize these dogs so that we can put them down.
举起手来  异教徒
拉马尔
Ramal.
拉马尔  你想干什么
Ramal, what are you doing?
你以为你能骗得过我吗
You thought you tricked me?
你绕了远路...
Take the long way around...
好让你的朋友...
while your friend...
先来这里拿武器
gets here first to get weapons.
你当时就是想坑我
You were going to screw me.
你们的美国俚语就是这么说的  对吧
That's the American slang, isn't it?
当时是你想坑我
You were gonna screw me.
看来我们俩的话都不可信
So much for our word.
对敌人撒谎
Lying to enemies.
这叫神圣的谎言
It's called Taqiyya.
打开照相机拍摄
Take off the camera.
我会让世界看到
I will show the world
耍阿布·拉马尔
what happens
是什么下场
when you screw Abu Ramal.
跪下
On your knees!
-想都别想  -让他们跪下
- It's not gonna happen. - Make them on their knees!
够了
Enough!
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
离我弟弟远点
Step away from my brother.
哥
Linc.
你有多爱你弟弟
How much do you love this brother of yours?
你最好下车
Why don't you step down from that truck?
停  停下  都住手
Stop. Stop, stop, stop.
不  这样下去不行  懂吗
No, it's not going down like this, okay?
住手  我还有好多问题要问我朋友
Just... stop. I got way too many questions for my friend here.
退后
Step back!?
我因在酒吧斗殴打死一个人进了监狱
I went to prison for killing a guy in a bar fight.
我甚至没想要打架  懂吗
I didn't even want to get into it, okay?
当时他张嘴就对我马子爆粗口
He starts talking yang to my girl.
我让他滚蛋
I tell him to beat it.
他拔了刀  我怒火中烧
He pulls a knife, and I see red.
下一秒
One second later,
我拿着他沾满血的刀  他的尸体倒在地上
I'm holding his bloody knife, and it's his body on the ground.
-你的身手可没那么快  -是秒杀啊
- You're not that fast. - One second.
拜托别这样干
Please don't do this.
你会输
You will lose.
听听你朋友说的
Listen to your friend.
我是在对你说  拉马尔
I'm talking to you, Ramal.
我说过了  从卡车上下来
I told you! Step down from that truck.
拿起你们的武器
Pick up your weapons!
你还有一秒钟时间不让那一秒的事发生
You've got one second till that one second happens.
去死吧
Go to hell.
他们的援兵来了
We got more coming!
这边还有更多敌人
And more over here!
麻烦大了
This is a big problem.
我们赶紧离开这里
Let's get the hell out of here.
纽约州
伊萨卡
你想见我们吗
You wanted to see us?
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
看看谁才是大坏蛋
Behold the villain.
这家伙是谁
Who the hell is this guy?
他是我哥
He's my brother.
他是我亲哥
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
简直不敢相信  不敢相信
I just can't believe this. I can't believe this.
当时在监狱里  为什么
Back at the prison. Why?
-你为什么要那样说  -我必须否认你
- Why did you say? - I had to deny you.
你当时... 在拍我的录像
You were... you were filming me.
不能让他们知道
They can't know.
不能让谁知道
Who can't know?
-不能让他们知道我要越狱  -谁
- They can't know I'm getting out. - Who?
我之后会解释一切  只是...
I'll explain everything later, just...
莎拉和麦克呢
Sara and-and Mike?
他们很好
They're good.
-他们没事  -感谢上苍
- They're fine. - Oh, thank God.
感谢上苍
Thank God.
问题越来越多了  是吧
Questions just keep piling up, huh?
是你
That's you.
我们都上电视了
It's all of us.
他们在说什么
What are they saying?
说ISIL占领了政府电视台
That ISIL has taken over the government station.
他们敬爱的领导人阿布·拉马尔壮烈牺牲
That their beloved leader, Abu Ramal, has been martyred.
是我们杀了他
That we're the ones that did it.
整个ISIL军队刚刚向我们宣战了
The entire army of ISIL just declared war on us.
越 狱 第五季第四集